## Marco Suárez

WEB DEVELOPER +44 07000 00000

jmarcosuarez@live.com

39 Havil Street

SE 7SD London es.linkedin.com/in/jmarcosuarez

London github.com/jmarcosuarez

I there's something that defines me is side-projects. I live and breathe web dev. One of my side-projects was so huge that it could perfectly be the seed for a great startup. Giving solutions so problems people have is my expertise and the need to find news and better ways to solve problems has been always at the back of my head.

## Skills & Areas of Interest

- Aesthetics, Ethics, Metaphysics, Nihilism
- Psychology, Ontology, Poetry, LATEX
- Voluntarism, Tragedy, Fact-value distinction
- Anti-foundationalism, Philosophy of history

## **Project History**

2016 – Present

Project Development Team – Spain Remote kanban team member Spain

- As a team member of a startup which aims internationally, I am proud of being part of the development team of his web app.
- Improve understanding of scrum values in complex project development
- Collaborate with team to understand items in the Product Backlog
- Deliver increment of product functionality in each sprint as set in goals
- Self-organize in how best to accomplish work
- Linting and testing code is emphasized during all the process
- Front-end technologies used are Node, React/Redux with Webpack
- Back-end technologies used are Express, Socket.io, GraphQL, MongoDB

2013 – 2016

Fincaspace - fincaspace.com – Spain Full stack web developer Spain

- As founder of Fincaspace, I solely developed a web app that manages the office work and documents in a homeowners' association making administrators more efficient in their communications
- Integrated user authentication with Google
- Use of Google Cloud Storage web service to store documents

SUÁREZ RÉSUMÉ – PAGE 1 OF 2

- Admin manages listings for different homeowners associations, with their apartments and users, as well as listings for documents published
- Admin can publish documents that are accessible to all homeowners instantly
- Bulk communication to all homeowners possible though email templates
- Front-end technologies used are ExtJS, a JavaScript MVC framework, which created all views and actions in the app
- Back-end technologies include Symfony3, an object oriented PHP framework. Chosen for the REST API cores of the app as well as for connecting to the MySQL database.
- Finally, the app has been loaded to a PaaS service provider called OPENSHIFT of RedHat, where deployment was made with Git version control.
- Wrote up technical manuals and user instructions. See http://guia.fincaspace.com

2011 – 2015 IGUANALOCALMEDIA – Spain Web designer / Marketeer Spain

- I have over 5 years experience in the creation of websites for companies in different sectors.
- I create work that improved the visibility of clients
- Technologies used are Bootstrap and WordPress
- Notions learned range from copywriting, SEO, Google Analytics, Adwords and Facebook marketing

## Education

Bachelor Technical Engineering in Telecommunications (Bachelor)
University of Las Palmas de Gran Canaria (ULPGC)
Spain

• Equivalent to a bachelor's degree

2016 Online Course Modern React with Redux Udemy.com

• Master the fundamentals of React and Redux

2016 Online Course Advanced React with Redux Udemy.com

• Detailed walkthroughs on advanced React and Redux concepts

SUÁREZ RÉSUMÉ – PAGE 2 OF 2